Herman Loh

Front-End Developer, Software Engineer & Ex-Bootcamp Teaching Assistant

CONTACT INFORMATION

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/hermanlyx

Website: github.com/hurrmun | hermanloh.com

Email: hermanlyx@gmail.com

A design student who fell into the rabbit hole of web development. Inspired by the capabilities of modern web technology, I strive to create applications that leverage creative designs with well-written code to enhance and create experiences for people. Avid tech-enthusiast, educator, and lifelong learner.

SKILLS

Languages – JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Python

Technologies – React, Express, MongoDB, Heroku, Testing Library with Jest, TailwindCSS, ChakraUI, MUI, jQuery

Other Skills – Adobe Creative Cloud, Figma, Design Thinking, Graphic & UI/UX Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ufinity | Associate Software Engineer | Mar 2022 - Present

- Implemented UI using front-end libraries such as React, Redux, Redux Toolkit, React Hook Forms, and MUI.
- Unit, functional testing, and bug fixing for various UI components using Jest and React Testing Library.
- Worked in AGILE environment, with CI/CD over multiple sprints along with integrating new Back-End APIs.

General Assembly | Instructional Associate | Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

- Conducted lessons in Full-Stack Software Development with JavaScript, React, Express and MongoDB.
- As a Teaching Assistant, enabled students to achieve their goals to be industry-ready Software Engineers.

Republic of Singapore Air Force | Service Medic | Dec 2019 - Aug 2021

- Introduced a new patient management system, streamlining appointments between doctors and patients.
- Created numerous designed posters and videos for RSAF's Healthy Lifestyle & Anti-smoking Campaigns.

Sixmoredays | Digital Design Intern | Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

- Produced website mock-ups & social media assets and contributed to pitches & projects taken by the company.
- Created layout designs for web banners, interactive social posts & digital marketing with Facebook post hacking.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive | 2021

- Designed and implemented 4 projects using various web technologies including *JavaScript, Node.js, React, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Python, Django, REST APIs, Tailwindcss, Heroku, and Vercel.*
- Graduated as one of the top few students and was offered a role as a Teaching Assistant for the next class.

Singapore Polytechnic | Diploma in Visual Communication and Media Design | 2016 - 2019

- Organizing Committee for AY2017/2018 Freshman Orientation Program, a five-day event that catered to over 400 new students (Secretary / Treasurer role) & Subcommittee for Design School Club CCA from 2017 2018.
- Ambassador for SP's Design School and participated in various open house events as a student counsellor.

PROJECTS

Financial Independence Calculator | Personal Project | GitHub | Website

- Front-end web application created using React. Chakra UI. React Hook Form with Yup. and ChartJS.
- Compound interest calculator for multiple accounts, created to track your net worth after investing over time.
- Application calculates and displays information by year in a line chart for easy viewing and is mobile responsive.

QuizSG | Hack for Public Good by Open Government Products | GitHub

- Led creation of design screens for landing page, quiz taker & quiz maker flow using the OGP design system.
- Implemented UI/UX elements with Front-End technologies such as Typescript, React, and Chakra UI.
- Worked with a team of experienced software engineers to solve real problems that government officers are facing.

Daily Report | Report App Concept for a Concrete Supply Company | GitHub | Website

- Full-stack application made using React, Express, Node.js, PostgreSQL with knex query builder, and Heroku.
- Report app created to optimize a real use case of writing reports for material supplies on an excel spreadsheet.
- Implemented authentication with JsonWebToken, secure password hashing with bcrypt, and validation with Yup.

BuildAWT | Workout Building Tool | GitHub | Website

- Front-end web application built with React, TailwindCSS, and React Router with 3rd party API integration.
- Implemented public API (wger API) that returns different exercises sorted by equipment and category.
- The app categorizes the data from the API, which the user can search for and add to their workouts.